## **PERSONAL RESUME**



# Michael Zhao

## Basic info

- Region: Guangzhou
- D.O.B.: 1988.8.7
- Political status: None

#### Contact

- 13660113008
- flybirdgroup16@gmail.com

#### Self-assessment

Work ability: Accumulated profound work experience in project management. Familiar with overall management of the project with the control of essential processes and the smooth implementation.

Comprehensive ability: Excellent at communication and team management with logical thinking and execution. Able to work under pressure and love to accept challenges.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **Sun Yat-Sen University**

ter of Business Administration 2019-2022

-- Master of Business Administration
University of North Carolina at Pembroke

Pembroke, NC, United States

-- Bachelor of Science (Exchange Program)

2008-2010

**Guangdong University of Finance and Economics** 

Guangzhou, China

Guangzhou, China

-- Bachelor of Science

2007-2011

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Gientech Technology (Pactera)**

### **Senior Engineer**

2020-2022

- Based in HSBC Bank and work as Tech Lead /Team lead to manage, guide and support colleagues. Responsible for the Agile project management of Financial IT Projects.
- Adopt the Agile processes/principles/methods (daily tools: JIRA, confluence) and to lead development team to complete the delivery of each project
- Designed and developed general ETL programs with the establishment of cloud infrastructure, allocation of ETL jobs, and tracking of the testing process.
- Under English working environment, conduct daily communications with project stakeholders in Australia, Europe, India, Hong Kong and other countries/regions, to remove obstacles of the project

# Fengcheng Machinery Leasing (Aopu Trading)

#### Partner

2014-2020

- Responsible for the overall project management work of sales channel in overseas markets. Established North American & European Business for the company from 0 to 1.
- Integrating different sales channels to obtain orders details, product reviews and do product improvement.
- Utilized data to train and build models to generate sales prediction report which benefit for stock inventory management.
- Responsible for coordinating and managing the whole process of overseas business: local market/competitor/product research and analysis, product design/improvement, Channel negotiation, logistics, factories coordination, payment collection, social media marketing, customer service, etc.

#### **Self-employment**

#### Freelancer Entrepreneur

2012 - 2014

Analyzed and selected products from suppliers, identified niche market, conducted market research, did competitors' analysis and sold products to different markets.

#### **IPROCHEM**

#### **Foreign Trade Sales Assistant**

2011-2012

- Worked and communicated regularly with vendors, warehouse, sales, and logistics departments
- Maintained regular updates for shipping schedules, stock status, delivery status tracking & problem solving, etc.

#### Project

#### **Project: Cloud Data Solutions**

#### Duties:

- Prepare the Data migration plan, and design the technical solutions of data migration.
- ➤ Lead the team to develop SQL/scripts with proper work assignment. Migrate data from on Perm to BigQuery on Google Cloud via Juniper.
- Organized materials for customers and optimized user training materials, user operations manuals, and go-alive FAQ, etc.
- Responsible for the business cooperation work with project stakeholders globally, for related Data Migration solutions
- Inspection, measurement and testing to verify the outputs to meet stakeholders' acceptance criteria. Coordinated with various parties with the notify of assistance work before go-alive. Notified the schedule of the plan prior to assist in the go-alive work.

#### **Project: Report Generation Automation**

#### **Duties:**

- > Organized the report with proper work assignment based on requirements.
- Dealt with high volume data issues of the report via GCP native component Dataproc(Spark). Utilized scalable native cloud platform component for reliable elastic processing.
- Lead Team to build up a server in Google Cloud and setup connection to outbound data to Perpetual's server via SFTP.
- Prepared reports based on the data structure with the integrated upstream data sources and prepared production reports based on the data structure with specific parameters.

#### Others

- Cloud computing exploration and big data processing
- Customer classification and recommended projects
- Competitors' analysis project

#### **Certifications or Skills**

- Language skills: Trilingual in English (business level), Mandarin(native) and Cantonese(native)
- > Office skills: Proficient in Microsoft Office; Confluence; JIRA
- ➤ IT Skills:
  - Coding: Skilled in Python, Spark, Linux, Flask, Terraform, SQL.
  - Devops: Kubernetes, Jenkins, Docker, GCP Cloud
  - Analysis: Understand the common concept of Machine Learning, like Supervised learning & Unsupervised learning.
  - Version Control: GitHub Management
- > IT certification:
  - ➤ Google Cloud Certified-Professional Data Engineer
  - ACP (Alibaba Cloud Computing Engineer),
  - > ACA (Big Data Assistant Engineer)
  - > HCIA (Huawei Artificial Intelligence Engineer)